JULIO CID BEROIZA SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Front-End Engineer with 5 years of experience in supporting, maintaining, and deploying applications over extensive infrastructure, specializing in Angular. I have experience developing libraries and components in large-scale projects, working with large teams, and directly with clients. I have served as a technical lead in developing payment gateway projects in the retail sector. Additionally, I have experience in continuous deployment (CI/CD) of applications and in developing web applications using TypeScript, JavaScript, and Node.js.

Email: julio.cid.b@gmail.com Phone: +33 7 66 95 23 80 LinkedIn: <u>Julio Cid Beroiza</u> Lyon, France

Experience

Software Engineer

FEMSA

September 2023 - now

- Corrected critical errors on the e-commerce platform, improving usability and conversion rates.
- Developed and resolved service issues using NestJS, Typescript, and Jest for testing.
- Sought and implemented improvements to maintain clean and efficient code.

Software Engineer

Reign/Apply Digital

July 2021 - September 2023

- Developed component libraries using technologies such as Angular, Tailwind, Storybook, TypeScript, among others.
- Led the front-end team in developing a new checkout process.
- Successfully deployed an e-commerce platform in three countries in less than 6 months.

Software Engineer

Everis NTT Data

January 2021 - July 2021

- Designed and developed interactive models and features using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and the Angular framework.
- Managed and integrated API data in JSON format, precisely adapting them to the functional needs of the presentation layer, ensuring a smooth and efficient user experience.

Soft Skills

- Passion
- Time management
- Teamwork

- Adaptability
- Critical thinking
- Continuous learning

Hobbies

- Climbing
- Cycling
- Hiking

- Investing
- Reading

Technical Skills

Frontend:

Javascript, Typescript, React, Angular, HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Webpack, NPM, Devtools, Microservice

Backend:

NodeJS, express, NestJS, Java, Springboot, Linux, , Redis, Restful APIS, Python, ServerSide, Cookies, Unit testing, CORS

Databases:

SQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Redis, Contentful, OMS

Cloud:

Firebase, Google Cloud Platform(GCP), Maps, Re-captcha

Others:

Github, Git, Github Actions, Bitbucket, OOP

Academic Education

Automation and Control University Federico Santa María, Chile 2014 - 2018

Continuous Learning

Codecademy: Frontend Engineer

Udemy: JavaScript: Understanding the Weird

Parts

Udemy: Node.js, Express, MongoDB & More **Platzi:** Fundamentals of Software Architecture **Platzi:** Course on AWS: Cloud Computing

Fundamentals

Google: Generative Al

See certifications: <u>Licencias y certificaciones</u> | Julio Cid Beroiza | LinkedIn

Languages

- Spanish
- English
- French